<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workstation on Sandors Systems Scribbles</title>
    <link>https://theargo.io/tags/workstation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workstation on Sandors Systems Scribbles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://theargo.io/tags/workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Ansible</title>
      <link>https://theargo.io/post/installing_ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theargo.io/post/installing_ansible/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Need to deploy an Ansible Controller to run Playbooks from that uses the latest build and is easy to upgrade/configure.
The Solution Install Ansible from the latest release on GitHub.
The Goal Create an Ansible Controller directory that will run the latest version via git clone and setup the shell with the Ansible environment scripts.
Clone the Ansible repo Go to the GitHub project page github/ansible
Choose a release version or the dev branch and clone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add WebProxy Cert to Fedora</title>
      <link>https://theargo.io/post/add_webproxy_cert_to_fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theargo.io/post/add_webproxy_cert_to_fedora/</guid>
      <description>The Goal  Make Fedora work behind a restrictive idiotic corporate web proxy Install a corporate cert to make that happen  Get the cert Install the cert spudBud@pineApplez&amp;gt; openssl x509 -text -in /path/to/proxycert.crt &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/pki/tls/certs/ca-bundle.crt  The result Your corporate overlord has now man in the middled your personal gmail, have fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Update VirtualBox Guest Additions with vagrant-vbguest</title>
      <link>https://theargo.io/post/auto_update_virtualbox_guest_additions_with_vagrant_vbguest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theargo.io/post/auto_update_virtualbox_guest_additions_with_vagrant_vbguest/</guid>
      <description>The Goal  Keep the VirtualBox guest additions at the latest version using vagrant-vbguest built by dotless-de.  The Links  Vagrant - link
 Vagrant vbguest - link
 dotless-de - link
  vagrant-vbguest A beautifully simple Vagrant plugin to manage the guest additions on VirtualBox.
install spudBud@pineApplez&amp;gt; ~/Codestuff/vagrants/PuppetMaster $vagrant plugin install vagrant-vbguest  bootup usage vagrant-vbguest will run on every vagrant up or on a vagrant reload unless you specifically tell it not to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Vagrant Setup</title>
      <link>https://theargo.io/post/vanilla_vagrant_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theargo.io/post/vanilla_vagrant_setup/</guid>
      <description>The Goal  Setup Vagrant Start a Vanilla Ubuntu box  The Links  Vagrant - link  Vagrant Setup Grab the latest here Install it Thats it Adding Boxes When you add a box to your local puter it downloads the VM image to your home dir like so:
vagrant box add name url  spudBud@pineApplez&amp;gt; vagrant box add precise32 http://files.vagrantup.com/precise32.box  This downloads the VM image into the /boxes dir:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>